## RESUME

### VIGNESH.V

Email Address: hostgatordesigner@gmail.com | AlternateAddress: hostgatordesigner@yahoo.com

Mobile Number: (+91) 7708344737(Primary) | Landline Number: 0842-2210737(Secondary)

LinkedIn Profile: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/vignesh-v/4b/153/62b

### **Career Objectives:**

A good team player, who thrives on creating engaging creative solutions, is deadline orientated and has the ability to produce detailed technical specifications from client requirements.

A quick learner, who can absorb new ideas and can communicate clearly and effectively .Currently looking for an opportunity to join a dynamic, ambitious, growing company and forge a career as a first class website designer.

## **Key Skills:**

Word press | Web Designing | Graphic Designing | Dreamweaver | Adobe Photoshop | Base-Kit Designing | SEO | Google Analytics | PSD to Word press | Banner Designing | Web Services | PSD to HTML | Logo Designing | Layout Design | Mobile Apps Designs | Flyers Designing | Gaming Designs

### Language Skills:

HTML / XHTML | XML | CSS | JavaScript | PHP | MySQL | Flash

### **Software Skills:**

Microsoft Office | Photoshop | Dreamweaver | InDesign | ColdFusion | Spark | Base kit Editor | Big Commerce Tools

## **Highlights:**

Experience of 2+ years working in the IT department of a multinational organization

Working in a web project support environment and setting up processes

Excellent verbal and written communication skills and the ability to interact at all levels of the organization

Knowledge in WHCMS, CPanel working nature and through the company website support ticketing system.

Working knowledge of Microsoft Project and other Office tools

### **Achievements:**

Able to work cross platform from product to marketing campaigns.

Maintain the Creative bug brand through research, documentation and in every design effort

Design new web pages, product interfaces and collateral for marketing and product

Tactically execute at all stages of the design; from wireframes to vector and pixel level

Collaborate with designers, product managers, engineers and marketing

Conceptualize broad concepts and offer strategic, smart and elegant solutions

Give and solicit open and honest feedback as part of the design process

#### **Websites Delivered:**

http://bellaluceskincare.com/ http://www.chrisbabcockart.com/ http://www.foreverblessedtwins.com/ http://www.foreverblessedtwins.com/

http://www.masterbar.com.au/ | http://www.revolutiontextiles.ca/ | http://www.boulderkidspot.com/ | http://www.nhreventures.com/

http://www.dmagroup.co/| http://mmp.my

## **Work History:**

08/2013 - Present Glow TouchTechnologies (Homestead-Indian Operations), Mangalore

Module Lead - Web Graphic Designer (ITES Sector)

Evaluating, developing and proposing modifications to the team. Ensuring that the most appropriate teaching and learning methods are adopted in the delivery of the team.

Building E-Commerce website through Big Commerce software with possible features for a given shopping cart tools.

08/2012 - Previous Glow Touch Technologies (Hostgator-Indian Operations), Mangalore

Web Graphic Designer (ITES Sector)

Lead design team in creation and implementation of professional websites. Contributed to Graphic Designing /Web Designing through various professional templates by base-kit tools. Directed off-shore resources to create HTML for various online applications in support of outsourcing efforts.

09/2011 - 08/2012 Acme Software Technologies, Madurai

Graphic Designer / Web Designer

Cutting-Edge Technical Skills: Expertise in web usability, cross-browser environments, navigation, content management, technical development, and site metrics; assisted in design of first of its kind web application.

Branding: Designing& governing the use of corporate logos and Banner advertising.

08/2010 - 09/2011 Aj Square Technologies, Madurai

Graphic Designer (Game / Mobile Apps)

Highly productive and collaborative Graphic Designer; consistently achieve top-notch results that are on-time, on-budget and exceed customer expectations.

Work for Gaming design backgrounds and mobile apps effects.

### **EducationInfrastructure:**

05/2007 - 05/2010P.S.R.Engneering College, Sivakasi

Education level: Graduate School, Finished: Yes

# Other Language Skills:

English(R, W, S) | Tamil(R, W, S) | Telugu (S) | Hindi(R, W, S)

Location:

Native: Madurai, Tamilnadu

Current: Mangalore, Karnataka